one that is [music] lower today
following its third quarter earnings.
The bank's profit fell uh due to
provisions after the RBI directed the
bank to make a standard asset provision
of nearly 1,300 cr rupees. The key
positive however was the reappointment
of Sundi Bakshi as the MD and CEO of the
bank for 2 years. Ridd
>> well yes the suspense is finally over
the board of ICIC bank finally approving
that 2-year extension for Sandep Bakshi
to continue as the MD and CEO till 2028
and that ends months of speculation over
whether the man who was credited with
turning around the bank is going to stay
on at the helm or not. Now, Sundep
Pakshi took charge of ICICI Bank uh in
2018 following Chandakocher's
controversial exit at a time when the
bank if you remember was battling very
high NPA's volatile earnings and of
course governance concerns. Now, since
then he's kept a very quiet low profile.
You hardly ever see him on TV. He stayed
away from the headlines as well and cut
to the present. The bank is now among
the strongest performers in the private
banking space. It is in fact out pacing
peers on profitability and return ratios
as well. Now he is an ICICI group
veteran joined in uh 1986 went on to
lead ICICI Lombard then ICICI approval
life insurance. He was brought in as COO
of ICICI bank in mid 2018 when Chandaka
proceeded on leave following the video
controversy eventually took over as CEO
in October that year. Now during his
tenure he's made quite a pivot from the
previous regime exiting the aggressive
bulk corporate lending we saw under
Chandanda Kocher shifted to risk
calibrated growth the term which the
bank has grown to be associated with
focus more on retail MSME grow granular
loans overall and the result of this
pivot has been quite visible because in
the seven years under Sepakshi ICICI
bank's return on assets has jumped
sixfold while the return on equity has
risen nearly five times uh from 3.2% 2%
to 15.8%
as of the 9 months completed in FI26.
The annual profits have also surged
annually from about 3,300 crores to
47,000 crores now, which is a 14 times
jump in six years and continuing to
grow. Now, G's growth has also been very
disciplined. Advances and deposits both
have expanded 2 and a half times during
his tenure. Deposits stand at about
16.59 lakh cr up from 6.62 lakh crores
in FY19.
But one of the clearest improvements
under Sundep Bakshi has been in asset
quality. Gross NPA falling very sharply
from 6.7% to just one and a half% and
that is a four-fold cleanup of the loan
book as well. No wonder then
shareholders have also rewarded this
transformation. ICIC bank stock climbed
from barely 300 rupees in 2018 to more
than 1,400 rupees as of the last close
on Friday and that's a 365% gain under
Sep Bakshi. So from cleanup to
compounding the board is once again
trusting the architect of the bank's
turnaround to keep the momentum going
and the numbers surely are making a
strong case for him.
>> All right, we take that point. Thanks a
lot for that. Uh, another